A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - Northwest Chicanos, 1976-1993; (2 folders; see also: Arreguín, Alfredo) (Box 21, Folder 25-26)
    (brochures; reprint of The Unique Psycho-Historical Experience of the Mexican-American People by Rodolfo Alvarez, 1971; letters to TYF from: Rodolfo Alvaraz, 12/02/1969; and from Teres Elguezabal de Pyne, Washington State University, 022/1971; documents related to an independent study done with TYF; exhibition catalog essays by TYF on Alfredo Arreguín and Susan Lytle; flyer; meeting minutes of the Chicano Education Association, 02/23/1974; letter to TYF from Pat [former student of TYF]; "Chicano Cultural Expression in the Pacific Northwest Directory Chican/Latino Cultural Interpreters; photograph; exhibition announcements; clippings; reports from Evergreen State College; note to TYF from B. Thomas, 08/28/1988; photocopy of letter to Erasmo Gamboa from TYF, 06/03/1988; color photographs, not labeled)
  - Northwest Chicanos - Newsletters/Newspapers, 1974-1988 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    ( La Voz Unida, Portland Oregon, Jan. 1974; The Daily, Seattle, Washington, Feb. 11, 1975 and May 9, 1975; Northwest, The Sunday Oregonian Magazine, Oct. 25, 1987; La Voz, Seattle, Washington, Aug. 1988)
  - Las Notícías, Newsletter, Pasadena, California (see also: Folk Art), 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    (issues Nov./Dec. 1986; Feb./March 1987; Nov./Dec. 1989)
  - Nuestro, Magazine, New York and California, April 1978 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - El Nuevo Mundo: The Landscape of Los Angeles (see also: Photography), 1999; (invitation; exhibition announcement/program schedule) (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Nuño, Domingo, Performance Artist, circa 1997 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    (member of "los Tricksters;" invitation; press release; exhibition announcement; color photographs; Mercedes Chavez Ponazanelli resume; The Indecisions of El Rio Bravo installation catalog)
  - Ochoa, María, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    (letter to TYF from Ochoa, 09/20/1994, with abstract and prospectus of her dissertation, and resume)
  - Ochoa, Ruben, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    (essay by Ochoa)
  - Ochos de los Ochenta, Exhibition, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1986; (catalog) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - O'Higgins, Pablo, Painter and Muralist (see also: Murals), 1975, undated; (clippings) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Olguín, Ben, undated; (dissertation prospectus; photographs) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Olguín, Rick A., circa 1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    (letter to TYF from Olguín, 12/13/1989, with article and grant proposal)
  - "On the Subject of Gang Photography,", 2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    (article by Richard T. Rodríguez)
  - Ortega, Gil (see: Graffiti) (Box 22)
  - Ortega, Eriberto and Esteban, 2003; (clipping; see also: Photography) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Ortega, Tony (see also: Colorado; Rivera, George), circa 1984-1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    (clipping; book, A Migrant Child's Dream: Farm Worker Adventures of Cholo, Vata, and Pano, 1994, with story by George Rivera and illustrations by Ortega; resume; catalogs; exhibition announcements; letter to TYF from Ortego, 02/05/1988)
  - Ortíz Torres, Rubén, 1991, 1993; (clippings) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Osorio, Pepón, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    (exhibition announcements; note to TYF from Osorio, 5/16/1996; essay on Osorio and his comments on it; clippings; press release)
  - Other Sources: An American Essay, Exhibition, San Francisco Art Institute, 1976; (clipping; catalog) (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Pacheco, Arturo, 1983-1984; (clippings) (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Pacheco, Ferdie, 1998; (exhibition announcement) (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Pachuco Publishing Company, Los Angeles, California, 1976, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    (publication announcements; TYF's notes on "Pachuco" and "Recuerdos del Palomas"; information on the company)
  - Los Pachucos (see: Cholos) (Box 22)
  - Packard, Emmy Lou, Painter (1914-1998; see also: Emmy Lou Packard Papers; Rivera, Diego), 1981-1985 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    (resume; postcard to TYF from Packard, 09/18/1983; letters to TYF from Packard, 09/04/1983, 11/01/1985, 11/24/1985; essay about Packard by Diego Rivera; hand- written and edited draft of Packard's "book" on Diego Rivera's San Diego frescoes)
  - Palomino, Ernesto, Artist and Educator (1933-), 1956-1981 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    (book, In Black and White: Evolution of an Artist, Academy Library Guild, Fresno, California, 1956, signed by the author; clippings)
  - Paño Arte (see also: Museum of International Folk Art), 1971-1997, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
    (clippings; exhibition announcements; Mexican-American Self-Help (MASH) Seminar Report on Prison Reform; exhibition guide; photographs of art and information about the exhibition Paño Art From the Inside Out, Museum of International Folk Art)
  - Parrilla, Eliezer, 1991; (oversize exhibition poster; see: Box 31) (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Los Pastores, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    (TYF's notes on Los Pastores)
  - Patlán, Ray, 1987; (clipping) (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - La Patria Portátil: 100 Years of Mexican Chromo Art Calendars, Exhibition, Museo Soumaya, Mexico City, and the Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, 1999; (exhibition catalog) (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Pazos, Antonio, 1977-1979; (clippings) (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Peña, Amado (see also: CARA), 1979-1991, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
    (exhibition announcement; clippings; CARA poster; press release; catalog)
  - La Peña, Cultural Arts Center, Austin, Texas, 1989-1990, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
    (brochures; exhibition announcements; organization history and information; clipping; La Peña newsletter: vol. 1, no. 2 Jan./Feb. 1986; vol. 5, nos. 1 - 2 Feb./March - April/May 1990)
  - La Peña, Berkeley, Cultural Center, Berkeley, California, 1998, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    (events calendar; exhibition announcement; postcard)
  - Penitentes, circa 1951, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    (book, The Penitente Papers, by Charles Aranda, circa 1951; clipping)
  - Pérez, Gloria Ozuna, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    (clippings; catalog; artist portfolio with resume, slides, clippings and information on the exhibition, Coyolxauhqui: Madre Cosmica, El Paso Museum of Art, 1996)
  - Pérez, Laura Elise, 1988-1993, undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
    (essay by Pérez; letters to TYF from Pérez, 11/06/1989, 10/07/1992, 06/02/1993; resume)
  - Pérez, Marvette (see: Paño Arte) (Box 22)
  - Performance Art, 1989-1995, undated; (2 folders; see also: Fusco, Coco; Gómez-Peña; INTAR; Jimenez, Luis; López, Yolanda; Osorio, Pepón; SPARC; Theater) (Box 22, Folder 30-31)
    (clippings; Michael Rey Diaz resume; poem by David Cristiano Rubí y Diamos; invitation to Acciones and information about Acciones; note to TYF from Teresa, 08/14/1992; essays; Rompeforma '93 program; press release)
  - Photography (Box 22)
    - Con Cariño, Chicano Photography Exhibition, sponsored by Aztlán Cultural Center in Erlangen, Germany (see also: Aztlán Cultural Center), 1983, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 32)
      (background information; list of artists; part of grant proposal; letter to TFY from Robert [Buitrón?], 10/02/1992; photocopy of German catalog)
    - Chicano, 1980-1992; (2 folders; see also: Buitrón, Robert; Lucy R. Lippard Papers; Box 30) (Box 22, Folder 33-34)
      (catalogs; oversize exhibition poster with Lucy R. Lippard quotation; exhibition announcements; Center Quarterly A Journal of Photography and Related Arts, vol. 8, no. 3 Spring 1987 and vol. 9, no. 4 Summer 1988; exhibition announcemement/call for entries; TYF's notes - bibliographic information and contact information; The Americas: A Review of Hispanic Literature and Art of the USA vol. 17, no. 1 Spring 1989; The Silver Bulletin, Summer 1989, River City Silver, Inc., San Antonio, Texas; letter to TYF from Lisa [?], 08/07/1989, with photographs, not labeled; fax to TYF from Rose Marie [?], 10/19/1992, re. American Voices exhibition; clippings; letter to TYF from Mereida García Ferraz, 06/28/????; list of photographers, p. 2 of 4)
    - Council on Latino Photography/USA (CLP/USA), 1979-1980; (see also: Box 30) (Box 22, Folder 35)
      (oversize exhibition poster; CLP/USA newsletter: no. 1 Jan. 1979, no. 2 Jan. 1980)
    - Cuba, 1985; (clipping) (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - En Foco, Inc., Organization, Bronx, New York, 1985-1995; (see also: Chicano Photographers; Box 30; OV 32) (Box 22, Folder 37)
      (brochure; oversize exhibition posters; catalogs, including: Events, En Foco, Inc., the Heresies Collective, and The New Museum of Contemorary Art, New York, 1983; and A Decade of En Foco, Bronx Museum of the Arts and En Foco, Inc., Bronx, New York, 1986; letter to TYF from Davied Trend, editor, Afterimage, 09/30/1986; Sin Fronteras conference information; Nueva Luz: A Photographic Journal, vol. 3, no. 4 1992; Critical Mass newsletter: vol. 6, no. 2 Feb./Mar. 1988; vol. 9, no. 5 Oct./Nov. 1992; vol. 10, no. 4 Oct/Dec. 1993; vol. 12, no. 3 July/Aug. 1995)
    - Fotofest (see also: Bernal, Luis Carlos; Fusco, Coco), 1982-1994 (Box 22, Folder 38-39)
      (clippings; TYF's notes; press release; letters to TYF from [Wendy Watriss?], 10/12/1993 and 12/13/1993; grant application; letter to Wendy Watriss from Coco Fusco, 11/29/1993, with essay for Fotofest catalog; typewritten essays from the catalog; brochure; list of artists; press releases; fact sheet)
    - General, 1978, 1982, 1984, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 40)
      ( Foto News, Cityscape Foto Gallery, Pasadena, California, Feb. 1983; catalogs; clipping)
    - Hispanic/Chicano, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 41)
      (exhibition catalogs; clipping; TYF's notes, "Kathy: Directorial Mode: Assemblage & Construction," chicano photography; "Hispanic Expressive Culture and Contemporary Public Discourse" Seminar schedule)
    - Latin American, 1981-1988; (see also: Box 30) (Box 22, Folder 42)
      (clippings; oversize exhibition poster; exhibition announcements; TYF's notes on "Photography - Latin America")
    - Memoria de Papel: Crónicas de la Cultura En México, Magazine, Consejo Nacional Para la Cultura y Las Artes, San Ángel, México, April 1992 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Mexican (see also: Fusco, Coco; Iturbide, Graciela), circa 1984-1991 (Box 22, Folder 44)
      (clippings and photocopies of sections from books)
  - Photography continued (Box 23)
    - Museum of Photographic Arts (see also: Iturbide, Graciela), 1966, 1978-1997, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      (invitation; letter to TYF from Tara Holley, Museum of Photographic Arts, 06/19/1990; catalog; typescript of essay on photography, author unknown; clippings; book, Basta! La Historia de Nuestra Lucha, photos by George Ballis, text from the Plan of Delano, Farm Worker Press, Inc., Delano, California, 1966)
    - Publications, 1982-1988 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      ( Afterimage, Visual Studies Workshop, Rochester, New York: vol. 10, no. 5 Dec. 1982; vol. 11, no. 8 March 1984; vol. 12, no. 8 March 1985; vol. 15, no. 6 Jan. 1988; Photo Metro, Photo Metro, San Francisco, California; April 1987 issue featuring the Museum of Photographic Arts)
  - Pinto Culture (see: Olguín, Ben) (Box 23)
  - Plascencia, Luis F. B. (see: Cholos) (Box 23)
  - Plaza de la Raza, Los Angeles, California, 1981-2003; (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
    (folklife Festival catalog; newsletter: vol. 1, no. 2 June 1981; publication announcement; membership forms; exhibition announcements; course schedules; catalogs; invitation; clippings)
  - Plural, Magazine, Mexico City, Mexico, January 1993 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Pocho Art, 1968; (photocopy of exhibition catalog) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Pocho Magazine, Berkeley, California (issues 3, 5-8), 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - El Pocho Che, Magazine, Berkeley, California, circa 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Pogue, Alan, 1989; (resume; clipping) (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Popular Arts, Workshop and exhibition, Guadalupe Theater Gallery, San Antonio, Texas, 1987; (catalog) (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Popular Culture (see also: Cultura Popular), 1987, 1992, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
    (clipings; notes for Prof J. Flores' sociology course; bibliography)
  - Portillo, Lourdes (see also: Museum of Fine Art), 1988 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    (note to TYF from Portillo, 09/13/1988 and letter to TYF from Janet Cole, 09/19/1988, both re. the El Dia de Los Muertos Film Project)
  - Posada, José Guadalupe, 1980; (clipping) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "Post Chicano", 1999 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    (clipping of essay by Rita González)
  - Post-Colonial California, Exhibition, San Francisco State University Art Department Art Gallery, San Francisco, California, 1995; (see also: Chagoya, Enrique; Gómez-Peña, Guillermo; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Rascón, Armando) (Box 23, Folder 15)
    (exhibition announcement; catalog)
  - Posters (see also: Santos, Margaret) (Box 23)
    - Berkeley Chicano Studies Library, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      (list of "Posters/Prints/Reproductions;" bibliography; photocopy of essay on posters, with TYF's notes in the margins; TYF's notes on posters; "U.C. Berkeley Chicano Studies Library Non-Print Collections: A Field Study" report)
    - Cuban, 1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
      (clippings of articles; outline for "Presentation on Cuban Posters" by one of TYF's students)
    - General (see also: Santos, Margaret; White, Sid), 1984-1993, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
      (clippings; catalogs; typescript of "Hablamos/We speak: Contempory Chicano Posters"; letter to TYF from Margaret T. Santos, 09/01/1993; exhibition announcement; letter to TYF from Lydia [?], 01/15/1987; letter to TYF from Sid White, 01/13/1987; letter to TYF from Michael Rossman, 12/28/1986; TYF's notes on chicano posters, "Juan Fuentes", "Grafica Chicana", "The Chicano Movement: Context for Chicano Posters"; handwritten draft of letter to Sid [White] from TYF, undated; Art Journal issue on "The Poster", Spring 1984)
    - Mexican, 1967, 1977, 1992; (clippings) (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Puerto Rico, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      (photocopy of exhibition catalog, The Poster in Puerto Rico 1946-1985, University of Puerto Rico Museum, Rio Piedras Campus)
  - Precita Eyes Mural Arts Center, Organization, San Francisco, California, circa 1995 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    (brochure)
  - Pre-Colombian Art, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
    (clippings; TYF's notes on pre-Columbians and lecture notes)
  - Princeton University A Chicano Arts Festival, 1982; (catalog) (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Prints (see: Estampas) (Box 23)
  - Prisma, Multicultural Women's Literary Review, Department of Ethnic Studies, Mills College, California, 1979, 1982; (spring 1979 issue; invitation) (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - El Puente, Newsletter of the Hispanic Culture Foundation, Albuquerque, New Mexico, Vol. 5, No. 2, summer, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Pujol, Ernesto, 1997; (exhibition announcement) (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Quirarte, Jacinto, 1970-1990, undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
    (clippings and photocopies of Quirarte's essays, one signed to TYF; TYF's notes on Quirarte LACMA lecture; project proposal; TYF's notes on Mexican art and architecture history)
  - Quirarte, Jacinto - A History and Appreciation of Chicano Art, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    (bound volume, published by Research Center for the Arts and Humanities)
  - Quiróz, 1973; (clipping) (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Race and Classification: The Case of Mexican America, Symposium, Los Angeles Count Museum of Art, Los Angeles, California, 2004; (symposium announcement and invitation) (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Rafael Cintron Ortiz Cultural Center, University of Illinois at Chicago, 1986; (flyers) (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Raíces Antiguas/Visiones Nuevas, circa 1980 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    (essay by Olivier Debroise)
  - Rámirez, Chuck, 1999-2003 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    (clippings; exhibtion announcements; ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program brochure, 2002)
  - Rámirez, Martin, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    (clipping; catalog, The Heart of Creation: the Art of Martin Rámirez, Goldie Paley Gallery, Moore College of Art, Philadelphi, Pennsylvania, 1985)
  - Rámirez, Ramon, circa 2004; (booklet) (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Ramos, Denise, 2002; (clipping) (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Ramos, Henry A.J., 2002-2003; (exhibition announcement; booklet) (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Ramos, Juan Miguel, 2002, 2004; (exhibition announcements) (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Rasca Tripas, Newsletter, La Raza Student Union, Merritt College, Oakland, California, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    (vol. 2 nos. 1-2 Oct.-Dec. 1970; vol. 3, no. 1 Jan. 1971)
  - Rascón, Armando (see also: Blue Star Art Space; INTAR), 1987-1994 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    (catalog signed by Rascón, Xicano Anesthetic: Taking issue with Mrs. Belcher's American History Lesson, Fourth Grade, Jefferson Elemetary, Calexico, California, School Term 1966-1967, INTAR Gallery, New York, New York, 1994; exhibition announcements; clippings; press release; invitation; slide list for Occupied Aztlán; resume)
  - Rasquache (see: Kvinta, Paul) (Box 23)
  - Rasquachismo, Exhibition and Symposium (see: Movimiento del Rio Salado-MARS; and Sifuentes, Roberto) (Box 23)
  - Raya, Marcos, circa 1998; (booklet) (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Rayas, Newsletter of Chicano Arts and Literature, Albuquerque, New Mexico, No. 5, Sept.-Oct. (see also: Chicanas), 1978 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - La Raza, Magazine, Los Angeles, California, Vol. 2, No. 1 February, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - La Raza Bookstore, Organization, Sacramento, California (see also: Avalos, David; Galeria Posada; Lujan, Gilbert "Magu"), 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    (catalogs; exhibition announcements; clippings; book catalogs; brochure; newsletter: vol. 3, nos. 1 and 2, April and June 1990)
  - La Raza Graphic Arts Center, Inc., Organization, San Francisco, California (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24), 1979-1993; (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 45-46)
    (exhibition and event announcements; clippings; invitations; administrative documents including: "5 Year Plan, 1985-1989", financial statements, art advisory committee meeting minutes, proposals, meeting agendas; letters to TYF from Linda Lucer, Director La Raza Graphics, 03/16/1987, 04/01/1987; photocopy of letter to Linda Lucero from Moctesuma Esparza and Robert Redford, Milagro Productions, Inc., 01/19/1988)
  - La Raza Yearbook, El Barrio Communications Project, Los Angeles, California, September 1968 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - La Reconquista: A Post-Columbian New World, Exhibition, 3rd International Bienali Istanbul, Istanbul, Turkey (see also: Avalos, David; Centro Cultural de La Raza; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Sánchez, Robert), 1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    (catalog; clippings; memo to Marian Godrey, Pew Charitable Trusts and Suzanne Sato, Rockefeller Foundation, from Vanessa Palmer, Arts International, 10/30/1992)
  - Reencuentros/Reencounters: Expressions of Latino Identity in the Northwest of USA, Project of Washington State/Chile Partners of the Americas (see also: Alvarez, Celia; Arreguin, Alfredo; Calderon, Mark; Trejo, Rubén), 1993; (catalog) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Relámpagos Books, Publisher, Austin, Texas, 1985; (invoice; publications list) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Rentería, Philip, 1977, 1980; (clippings) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Renato Rosaldo Lecture Series, University of Arizona, 1976-1977; (brochure) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Resistencia Book Store, Austin, Texas, 1986; (newsletter) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Resolana, Annual Lecture/Retreat, Resolana Learning Center, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1988-1994 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    (administrative document: proposal; El Pregovero, Sawmill Advisory Council's newsletter, vol. 2, no. 2 August 1991; letter to TYF from [Tomás Atencio? - illegible], 06/09/1994; bound lecture by Tomás Atencio, with introduction by TYF)
  - Retablos y Ex-Votos, Exhibition, Washington State Arts Commission, 1985, 1998; (exhibition announcement; catalog) (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Revelaciónes/Revelations: Hispanic Art of Evanescence, Exhibition, Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (see also: Gronk; Martínez, Daniel; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Muñoz Alvarez, Celia; Noriega, Chon), 1993; (press release; information sheets; invitations) (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Revista Rio Bravo, Newsletter, Laredo, Texas, 1981-1983; (see Box 31; see also: De León, Nephtalí Goldman, Shifra; Peña, Amado) (Box 24, Folder 11)
    (vol. 1, nos. 1 - 3, Winter, Limited Edition, Fall, 1981; vol 2, nos. 1 - 2, Spring 1982, final issue 1983)
  - Reyes, Felipe (Box 24)
    - Slides (see also: Con Safo Group), 1974-1990, undated; (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
      (slides of works of art and of Reyes and other people)
    - Para Gente Magazín, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      (vol. 2, no. 4 April 1972 with art by Reyes)
  - Rifarte II, Poetry Reading and Exhibition, San Francisco, California (see also: Herrera, Juan Felipe), 1985; (invitation) (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Rio Grande Weaving, 1979, 1981; (clippings) (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Rios, Diego Marcial, Printmaker, 1984-1990, undated; (see also: Heisley, Michael) (Box 24, Folder 17)
    (exhibition announcements; slides of works of art; letters to TYF from Rios, circa 06/1987, 06/09/1988, 06/24/1988, 06/27/1988, circa 07/1988, 07/20/1988, 07/24/1988, 09/16/1988, 10/15/1988, 01/22/1989, 01/30/1989, 05/01/1989, 04/24/1990, 05/26/1990, undated; TYF's notes on Rios; resumes; clippings)
  - Rios, Richard and Graciela, 1981-1989 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    (clippings; exhibition announcement; resume; list of art works for sale)
  - Rivera, Diego, 1984-1988 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    (catalog with forward by TYF; chronology of Rivera's life; invitation; City of San Francisco's celebration of the 100th anniversary of Rivera's birthday program; exhibition announcement; clippings)
  - Rivera, George (see also: Colorado; Lucy R. Lippard Papers), circa 1992-2001 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    (slides of works of art; exhibition announcements; clippings; catalogs; resume; catalog with introduction by Lucy R. Lippard)
  - Rivera, Gregorio, 1990-1991 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    (slides of works of art; note to TYF from Rivera, 02/10/1991; artist's statement)
  - Rivera, Gustavo Ramos (see also: Ancient Roots/New Visions), 1979-1994, undated; (exhibition announcements) (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - The Road to Aztlán: Art From a Mythic Homeland, Exhibition, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, California (see also: Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Zamudia-Taylor, Victor), 2001 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    (clippings; exhibition announcement; photocopies of sections from the catalog: front matter, essays by Amalia Mesa-Bains and Victor Zamudio-Taylor)
  - Robleto, Dario, 1997-2004 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    (clippings, ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program 2000 brochures)
  - Rodríguez, Anita, 1988, circa post-1996; (clippings) (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Rodríguez, Artemio (see also: Galería sin Fronteras), 1999, 2002; (invitation; clipping) (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Rodríguez, Diana (see also: Alfaro, Luis), 1977; (wedding invitation) (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Rodríguez, Eugene, 2000, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    (essay by Rodríguez; letter to TYF from Rodríguez, 10/04/2004; catalog and press packet for the exhibition The Middle of Somewhere, Gallery 49, New York, New York, 2004; press packet includes exhibition announcement, press release; clipping; 2 CD-ROMs; resume; and color photographs of works of art)
  - Rodríguez, Freddy, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    (exhibition announcement; letter to TYF from Antonia Hernández, President and General Counsel, Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, 04/27/1990)
  - Rodríguez, Jesús, 1972, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 30)